Curriculum Vitae Darragh Martin

Tel: 0877810773

darraghjmartin@gmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/darragh-martin-61417512/

Profile

I am a professional with over 14 years of people and project management experience. I have a great understanding of how to run the company in always changing environment, create custom oriented business, how to plan budgets and create long lasting growth strategies. Professional with good negotiation and problem solving skills, strategic thinking and sharp logic. I am an open-minded and hard-working team player with excellent communication skills, great attention to detail and an analytical approach to problem solving. I am a fast learner, reliable and conscientious individual.

Professional Experience

Jan 2019 - July 2019

Milan Gaming Ltd – General Manager Operations

- Facilitated the seamless transfer of the business to the new owners
- Trained and oversaw the development of new staff in line with the structures of the new company, while also implementing the latest technology guidelines for new staff to follow
- Organised and led weekly catch ups with key stakeholders from around Ireland to discuss latest technology and operation strategy implementation in our 7 core locations to make sure it was running effectively and efficiently.
- Developed a business strategy that would help to scale the business as well as help us to keep our service on a high level and always deliver best in house experience to each and every customer in all 7 locations. Took responsibility for social interaction across social media channels to alert our customers to our latest competitions, offers and rewards programme.

October 2016 - December 2018

Marko Ltd – Executive Director

- Was instrumental in the initialising process whereby a very successful sale of the company's business as a going concern as well as a property portfolio associated with it took place.
- Implemented the latest software systems on all machines that calculated real time data to the main company database.
- Overhauled the company's customers database to compile with GDPR regulations
- Incorporated many computer programmes on company database to showcase company profit and loss accounts, future projections and latest machine software patches to maintain everything up to date to prevent machine shutdowns
- Set up a ticketing system from machines to in house ATM to give customers more control of their withdrawals and more privacy for them

August 2013 – September 2016

Marko Ltd – Operations Manager

- Interacted with other IT specialists around Europe when machines went down due to server problems and following step by step protocol to get them up and running

- Took charge of all casino operations & management of car park operation
- Successful introduction of technical revamp of systems whereby operations to control accounting feedback from individual gambling machines
- Linked all gaming machines to online jackpots for in house

August 2009 - July 2013

Marko Ltd - Facilities Manager

- Devising cash control and accounting systems to assist in assessing and reconciling the performance of diverse casino equipment as regards input of cash and pay out of winnings to casino customers
- Devised and implemented weekly management accounting reports on Excel
- Banking duties control including preparation of lodgements and preparation of invoice payments to suppliers
- Preparation of weekly payroll in association with auditors

July 2005 - July 2009

Marko Limited – Staff Manager

 Work on floor as supervisor in casino, liaise with customers, dealing with technical problems on casino equipment, cash collections from casino equipment, cash control duties in cashier office, control supervising duties and liaising with all staff on day to day basis and coordinating working rotas

April 2002 to October 2002

Irish Life & Permanent (Dublin) - Internship

- Implemented key data from their client list into spreadsheets
- Weekly board meetings to discuss various issues that needed addressing
- Worked with a small group to implement the Irish Life Census forms to all their employees over the country and to record and implement the data to their database
- Worked with other departments within from HR to Accounting to implement various tasks that needed doing from phone calls, emails, and various data that was requested on behalf of the company

Education and Qualifications

2019 - 2020 - Code Institute Dublin

Diploma in Software Development

- Graduated as a fully qualified Full-Stack Developer
- Worked on various projects on this course which allowed me a greater understanding around software development lifecycle and tools
- Tools/Languages covered: HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, SQL, AWS, Python, Mongo DB, UXD, Django.

2004 – 2005 – University of Limerick

International Management in Entrepreneurship Honours Degree

1997 - 2002 - American College Dublin

Bachelor of Arts in International Business Honours Degree

Jan – May '02 – Lynn University Boca Raton, Florida

Spent a semester studying at the well renowned university In Boca Raton as part of my degree.

Additional Information

Computer skills: Microsoft Office, Outlook, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Djanjo, SQL

Business skills: Great communication skills, negotiation, problem solving,

strategic thinking, high level of adaptability, fast learner, real team

player

Interests: Software Development, Music, Sports, Books, Films

References:

Available on request